Jewish Federation of Greater Hartford Collection 0006.023.001
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
- Series XVII: Planning and allocation
  - Planning and Allocation/Allocation Proposals of beneficiary organizations, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Allocation Proposals of beneficiary organizations, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/budget and recommendations, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Budget and recommendations, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Capital Needs Committee, 1990s-2000s, 1990-2009 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Cultural and Group Services Committee, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocation/Education and Continuity Subcommittee, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 17)
  - Planning and Allocations/Miscellaneous, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 17)
- Series XVIII: Planning and allocation
  - Planning and Allocation/Finance Committee Members, 1949-1951 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Finance Committee Minutes, 1949-1951 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Finance Committee Minutes, 1969-1972 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Human Services Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocations/Jewish Association for Community Living, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Kitchen Cabinet, 2002 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Members, 1949-1952 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Members, 1968-1976 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes 1949-1952 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Planning Committee Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Overseas committee, 2001 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Steering committee, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 18)
  - Planning and Allocation/Steering committee, 2000-2002 (Box 18)
- Series XIX: Federation History
  - History/Early history, two folders of photocopies of materials regarding the early Jewish Federation movement found in other libraries. Beatrice Alderman collected this information in preparation for a Masters Thesis at Trinity College in Hartford., undated (Box 19)
  - History/Act incorporating the Hartford Jewish Federation, 1945, photocopy (Box 19)
  - History/Affachiner, Rebecca, the "Betsy Ross of Israel", undated (Box 19)
  - History/Anniversary, 25th, 1970 (Box 19)
  - History/Anniversary, 50th, 1995 (Box 19)
  - History/Federated Jewish Appeal of Manchester, Merger with Hartford Jewish Federation, 1979 (Box 19)
  - History/Federation Relationships with Functional Agencies, pamphlet of speech by Saul Seidman, 1951 (Box 19)
  - History/Greater Hartford Jewish Federation, pamphlet describing the history of the Federation, c.1982-1985 (Box 19)
  - History/"Jewish Council" minutes and other material documenting the formation of a council, 1930s-1940s, 1930-1949 (Box 19)
  - History/Jewish Federation movement, copies of published articles and pamphlets on the Federation movement, undated (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Annual Campaign, undated (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Merger, undated (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Newspaper articles/History of the Jews in New Britain by Irving Rachlin, 1959, undated (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Newspaper clippings/Hungarian refugees, 1956 (Box 19)
  - History/New Britain Jewish Federation/Newspaper clippings/Miscellaneous, 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 19)
  - History/Notes by A. Goldstein for a speech, 1937-1938 (Box 19)
  - History/Notes, general unidentified notes about the history of the Federation., undated (Box 19)
  - History/Parson's Theatre: Charity Performance for the Benefit of United Jewish Charities, 1919 (Box 19)
  - History/Presidents/Miscellaneous information regarding Federation Presidents, 1944-present. Includes several copies of Presidents Invitational Dinner Program, 2000 that highlights achievements of each president's administration., 1944-2010 (Box 19)
  - History/Presidents/information compiled re video interviews of presidents, 2000 (Box 19)
  - History/Newspaper clippings about the early history of the Federation, undated (Box 19)
  - History/Notes compiled as part of strategic planning process, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 19)
- Series XX: United Jewish Charities (UJC), Council of Jewish Federations (CJF), Jewish Federation Association of Connecticut (JFACT)
  - UJC/Annual reports. 1919, 1922, 1923, 1924, 1919-1924 (Box 20)
  - UJC/Annual report 1935, 1936 (Box 20)
  - UJC/Annual report, 1939-1940 (Box 20)
  - UJC/pre-1912 organizational meeting (Box 20)
  - UJC/Miscellaneous, 1912-1919 (Box 20)
  - Council of Jewish Federations (CJF) is the national umbrella organization for the local Federations. This series contains publicity and other materials produced by CJF that are not specific to the local Federation., undated (Box 20)
  - CJF/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20)
  - CJF/Pluralism in Israel controversy, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 20)
  - JFACT/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 20)
  - JFACT/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 20)
- Series XXI: Beneficiary Agencies
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Education and Schools, undated (Box 21)
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Guidelines for Fundraising for Beneficiary Organizations, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Jewish Community Center/Staff/Leipzig, Jay, undated (Box 21)
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Jewish Social Service, Inc., survey of 1950 (Box 21)
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Agency Self-Assessment, 1986 (Box 21)
  - Beneficiary Agencies/Miscellaneous – documents listings or describing all agencies, undated (Box 21)
- Series XXII: Community Service Projects
  - Community Service Projects/Committee on Aging, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Committee for Enhancement of Jewish Identity for New Americans, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Community Leadership Initiative, 2001 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Cuban Jews, undated (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Ethiopian Jews, undated (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Gulf War projects, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects Ethnic Heritage Resource Center, 1977 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Hartford Shalom, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Habitat Havarim, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Hispanic Community Dialogue, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/International Naval Review, sponsors of ships from Israel, n.d., undated (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Israel at 50, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Israel/Miscellaneous, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Israel at 50, 1998 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Israel at 60, 2008 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Jerusalem 3000, 1996 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Jeruselemfest, 1987 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Jewish Information and Referral Service, undated (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/La'atid, Synagogues for the Future, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Missions to Israel, 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Operation Israel, 1972 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Partnership 2000 (Afula, sister town) 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Partnership 2000 (Afula, sister town) 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Project Renewal, (Afula, sister town) 1970s-1980s, 1970-1989 (Box 22)
  - Community Service Projects/Project Renewal, (Afula, sister town) 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 22)
- Series XXIII: Community Service Projects
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/Bar and Bat Mitzvah Twins, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/newspaper clippings and press releases, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/newspaper clippings and press releases, 1983-1984 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/newspaper clippings and press releases, 1989-1990 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/newspaper clippings and press releases, 1990-1991 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/newspaper clippings and press releases, 1991-1992 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/Resettlement, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Soviet Jewry/Resettlement, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Suburban, undated (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Summer Singles, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Teen outreach, 2001 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/"Who is a Jew?" Controversy, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Community Service Projects/Miscellaneous projects, undated (Box 23)
- Series XIV: Special Campaigns
  - Special Campaigns/Building Campaign, early 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Capital and Endowment Campaigns, feasibility Campaigns, 1998 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Community Capital Campaign, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Community Capital Campaign, 2000 – present, 2000-2012 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Hartford Stands with the People of Israel/Hezbollah, Lebanon War, 2006 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Israel Emergency Campaign, 2002 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Joint Endowment Development Proposal, 1996 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Report on Capital and Major Campaigns in Greater Hartford, issued by Coordinating Council for Federations, 1998, undated (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Russian Economic Crisis, 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - Special Campaigns/Miscellaneous campaigns, undated (Box 24)
- Series XXV: Special Campaigns: Walkathon
  - Special Campaigns/The Walkathon was an annual event that raised funds for Israel., undated (Box 25)
  - Special Campaigns/Walkathon, multiple folders, 1970-1980s, 1970-1979 (Box 25)
  - Special Campaigns/"Vision", undated (Box 25)
  - Special Campagins/"Voices", undated (Box 25)
- Series XVI: Strategic planning
  - Strategic Planning/The American Jewish Community in the 21st Century, paper by Donald Feldstein, council of Jewish Federations, mid 1980s (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Background Material, 2000 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Fundraising Strategies after September 11, 2001 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Committee on Opportunities, Pressures, and Emphasis, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Community Master Plan, The Mead Group, 2000 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Confronting Choice and Connecting to Community: Report of Strategic Planning, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Confronting Choice…Report of Strategic Planning/Committee, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Confronting Choice...Report of Strategic Planning Committee/Follow-Up, 1996- (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Creating a Vision for the Future…Community Update on Long Range Strategic Planning/Strategic Plan, 2000 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Hartford Jewish Communal Study, 1938 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Committee members, 1995 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Market Research Report, 1994 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Marketing and Communications, 1991 (Box 26)
  - Strategic Planning/Marketing Study by Dr. Gary A. Tobin, 1990. folder includes an article by Tobin on Jewish philanthropy in the 1990s (Box 26)
- Series XXVII: Strategic planning
  - Strategic Planning/Population Study, 1982 (Box 27)
  - Strategic Planning/Population Study, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Strategic Planning/Preparing for Our Future, Main Report, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Strategic Planning/Preparing for Our Future, Summary Report, 2000 (Box 27)
  - Strategic Planning/Public relations and Marketing Plan, 1989-1993 (Box 27)
  - Strategic Planning/Public relations and Marketing Plan, 1995-1996 (Box 27)
- Series XXVIII: Strategic planning
  - Strategic Planning/Report of Committee on Agency Revenue Enhancement, 1989 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/Report of Self-Study Committee, 1995 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/Reports issued by various Jewish philanthropies on the planning process, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/Seniors, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/strategic questions and answers from beneficiary organizations, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/Social Services Assessment Report by Comart and Associates, 1998 (Box 28)
  - Strategic Planning/Summary of Self-assessment, 1987 (Box 28)
- Series XXIX: Strategic planning
  - Population study/extra copies, undated (Box 29)
- Series XXX: (JCRC): A - H, including Holocaust Commemorations
  - JCRC/Board, undated (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Church-state separation, 1993 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Connecticut Jewish Community Relations Council, minutes, notes, correspondence with JCRC, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1989 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/constitution and by-laws, undated (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Council on Jewish Continuity, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Domestic issues, undated (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Elderly/housing and meals, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Hartford Courant, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Hartford Jewish Coalition for Literacy, undated (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Hebrew Home and Hospital, 1993 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Hillel college campaign, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1979 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1980 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1980s (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1981 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1982 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1983 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1984 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1985 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1986 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1987 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1988 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1989 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1990 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1991 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust Commemoration, 1992 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Holocaust survivors, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 30)
  - JCRC/Homeless, undated (Box 30)
- Series XXXI: (JCRC): Interfaith Projects
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Christian Jewish Task force, 1989-90, 1989-1990 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Middle East in Crisis Program, 1988 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Precious Legacy Exhibit, 1985 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/report on Seder, 1987 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/report on Seder, 1989 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Seders, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 31)
  - JCRC/Interfaith/Soup Kitchen project, 1987 (Box 31)
- Series XXXII: (JCRC): Israel-related projects
  - JCRC/Israel at 40, 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel at 60, 2008 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 3rd, 1987 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 4th, 1988 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 5th, 1989 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 6th, 1990 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 7th, 1991 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 8th, 1992 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel Symposium, 9th, 1993 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel, Community Gathering in Support of, 2002 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Eye on Israel, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Invasion of Lebanon, 1982 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Rabin, Yitzhak/Memorial Service, 1995 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Terrorism/ Intifada, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 32)
  - JCRC/Israel/Terrorism/, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 32)
- Series XXXIII: (JCRC): Projects, J-S
  - JCRC/Jewish Federation Association of Connecticut, undated (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Jewish Organizations and Synagogues List, 1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Jews for Jesus/Messianic Judaism, undated (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Kosovo refugees, 1990s (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Legislative, 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Legislative, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Legislative/Act Concerning Temporary Guardians, 1981 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Media, 1970s-1980s, 1970-1989 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Media, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Memorial service for teenage victims of terrorist attack, 2001 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Mines, Jeffrey, Committee Chair (1976-1984) (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Minutes, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/National Jewish Community Relations Council, 1980s-1990s, 1980-1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/National Jewish Community Relations Council/Joint Program Plan, 1970s-1990s, 1970-1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Newsletters, undated (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Newspaper clippings, 1990s-2000s, 1990-2009 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Newspaper clippings/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Planning, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Pursuing Peace Forum, 1988 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Regional Consultation on Mid East Crisis, 1988 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Religious Liberty Restoration Act, 1990 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Scholar in Residence, 1986 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Scholar in Residence, 1987 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/Scholar in Residence, 1989 (Box 33)
  - JCRC/September 11, 2001, response of JCRC (Box 33)
- Series XXXIV: (JCRC): E - Soviet Jewry
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Clippings about "refuseniks," 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Dodd, Susan, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Dodd, Christopher, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Emigration, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Freedom for Jewry Sign, 1987 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Freedom Sunday, 1987 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Glasnost-Refuseniks, 1987 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Hungerfast, 1984 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Interfaith Committee, 1988 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Ioffee family, 1987 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/New England Conference, 1986 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Rally, 1982 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Rally, 1983 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Rally, 1985 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Rally, 1986 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/State and Local Officials for JCRC/Soviet Jews, 1988 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Summit II Petition drive, 1987 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Survival of the Spirit Photo Exhibit, 1988 (Box 34)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 34)
- Series XXXV: (JCRC): Soviet Jewry/Voices for Freedom and Women's Plea
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, Main file, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, outreach committee, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, site/facilities committee, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, celebrities committee, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, entertainment committee, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Voices for Human Freedom Rally, vendors, 1990 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women supporting women – "refusenicks," 1987 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1970s-1980s, 1970-1989 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1984 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1985 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1986 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1987 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1988 (Box 35)
  - JCRC/Soviet Jewry/Women's Plea for JCRC/Soviet Jewry, 1990 (Box 35)
- Series XXXVI: (JCRC): World Jewry
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Bosnia Forum, 1993 (Box 36)
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Conference, 1989-90, two folders, 1989-1990 (Box 36)
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Task force, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 36)
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Task force, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 36)
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Task force/From Russia to Israel with Love fundraiser, 1990 (Box 36)
  - JCRC/World Jewry/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 36)
- Series XXXVII: (JCRC)
  - JCRC/History/minutes, 1949-51, 1949-1951 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/History/minutes, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/History/Survey of Community Relations in Connecticut by Isaiah Terman. 1953 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/History/formation, 1952 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Israel Town Hall Meetings, 2003- (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous programs, announcements, etc. 2 folders, undated (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous programs, announcements, etc., 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous programs, announcements, etc. 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous programs, announcements, etc., 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Miscellaneous programs, announcements, etc. 2000-present, 2000-2009 (Box 37)
  - JCRC/Telegram Bank, 1950s-1960s, 1950-1969 (Box 37)
- Series XXXVIII: Newspaper Clippings; Publications
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 38)
- Publications:
  - Publications/Legacy, 2000
  - Publications/Straight Talk, 1990-1994
  - Publications/Volunteer Update, 1996
  - Publications/Roll of Honor, 2010, 2012
- Publications: Oversize Box 1:
  - Publications/Community Voice, 1970s-1980s. sorted by year into folders., 1970-1989
- Publications: Oversize Box 2:
  - Publications/FYI, 1996-2002
- Newspaper Advertisements: Oversize Box 3
  - Full page Federation and predecessor Jewish Charities advertisements, undated
- Series XXXIX: Chai – The Center for Jewish Life
  - Chai/Opening, 2004 (Box 39)
  - Chai/brochures, undated (Box 39)
- Videotape Series I:
  - Videotapes/No. 6, Part I August 2, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Videotapes/No. 10, Wedding of David Lavender at Jabotinsky House, Tel Aviv Israel, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Videotapes/No. 5, Sun Frost Ltd., Arhdad, Israel, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Videotapes/No. 9, Tekoah, Israel, August 8, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Videotapes/Operation Moses, undated (Box 1)
- Videotape Series II:
  - Videotapes/2000 campaign (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/Connecticut connection – project renewal, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/Generations, Nov. 1989, 3copies (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/News clips, Sept. 1988 – February 1992, including thank you America on Jewish LifeIntro, Convoy from Sarajevo/Fed/Aliyah/Extro/January 29, 1993, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/Presidents tributes, undated (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/Israel 40, 2copies, undated (Box 2)
  - Videotapes/Tovah Feldshuh, June 1, 1995 (Box 2)
- Audiotape Series I:
  - Alexander Slepak, undated (Box 1)
  - Zeev Sharef, October 26, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Project renewal, the vision of a model society, October 5, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Listen to out voices response to the 1977 UJA Prime Minister's Mission, united Jewish Appeal (Box 1)
  - Irving Bernstein, 1st National young Leadership conference, the case for 1978 (Box 1)
  - This year in Jerusalem ceremony at the Wall, Oct. 24-31, 1976 (Box 1)
  - 1975 – UJA, "We are One" (Box 1)
  - Abba Eban, Message to American Jewish Community, Oct 12, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Golda Meir; a message to the American Jewish Community, Oct. 1973 (Box 1)
  - Ma'a lot – May 15, 1974, eyewitness Jay Bushinsky (Box 1)
  - United Jewish Appeal, take home solicitor training course, 1975, 1957 (Box 1)
  - United Jewish Appeal, take ho9me solicitor training course, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Operation upgrade; the issue of immigration, a conversation with Ralph Goldman and Bud Levin, undated (Box 1)
  - Herschel Blumberg conference call on Israel emergency, June 9, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Family Scene, November 1975 (Box 1)